Oh so someone is out here.
Surprising, this time of night.
I'm out here sometimes, just singing to myself.
Um that song doesn't have a name, only a little tune I thought of this morning.
I thought I'd come out here to try it out in peace.
I don't live far from here, so I take the occasional walk.
Do you live nearby?
It is peaceful out here, yes.
It's why I like coming out here to sing in peace.
It's too loud where I live, and there's always interruption.
Come sit with me.
I enjoy splashing the water bit.
I only go into town for basic necessities.
I try to avoid it.
Is that what we are all about?
What we do?
I'd rather know what you like, what you care about.
Sure, I am unemployed, if you want to call it that.
Can't we play out this little mystery a bit longer?
You've met strangers in the night, and you ask if they have a job?
Singing feels like a job sometimes.
If only I had someone to hear me sing, even just a little.
.
It might not be a familiar tune, but I have had it on my mind for a while.
I feel like I'm not singing it strongly enough.
Voice carries a power that can break through walls and travel long distances.
You don't know where I first heard this melody, and yet I've brought it to you.
And if you learned it, you can take it anywhere to anyone.
When I sing, I want my voice to turn heads, stir hearts.
It can invade minds and lie dormant into some wake moment in your mind.
Even soulless sounds like commercial jingles have that power.
Um I don't know about that.
I can sing whatever I want right now, and I can sing for whoever I want.
Um my family is, um, complicated.
My singing doesn't stand out, really.
We are all singers.
It's just, I just want to sing for fun.
Um
our reasons for singing are really different.
You wouldn't understand.
My family and I, we are sirens.
We're sometimes called mermaids too.
I'm not going to do anything to you.
It takes a while to transform my tail into legs anyway.
If you want your own, just go ahead.
I don't just tell anyone what I am.
I have to be careful.
We all do.
We travel between water realm trying to stay hidden.
We've even resulted to hiding in lakes.
No, I don't live in this lake.
My family hasn't found this one yet, so I use it to just be alone sometimes.
My family's gotten a little aggressive lately.
There are lots of sirens out there.
But with more and more humans infiltrating more parts of the ocean, we have to keep running.
I'm going to pretend you didn't make a "just keep swimming" joke at me.
I can't really stop you, but still, please don't tell anyone about me.
I won't come back here again.
I'm not supposed to talk to humans anyway.
My family's joined some other sirens trying to get back at humans or whatever.
They've been following large boats to reel humans into the sea.
It was my family's idea to go after cargo ships.
That's not possible.
There are so few sirens left in the world.
All we're doing is just buying time until we all die out.
It's simply over for us, and they just refuse to accept it.
I don't know what else to do or where to go.
I can only do a few hours out of water, and walking with my leg is so tiring.
I just try to stay out of their way.
Besides, it's not like they need me anyway.
I wouldn't be useful.
I can't walk a lot or do much, just sit and sing in one place.
What do you mean stay with you?
Why? Why would you do that?
That's sweet, but I don't know.
What would I even do?
I wouldn't want to be an inconvenience to you.
Fine. I, I do want the offer.
Yes, I want to stay with you.
Yeah, go ahead.
I will wait here.
It will take me a minute to get my legs going anyway.